Asadullah Farooqi

Software Engineer

+923111686184 asadullah.itcgcs@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Maher Inc, Lahore — Software Engineer

Feb 2019 - Present

<u>Maher Inc</u>, Lahore — Full stack Engineer Internship

DEC 2018 - JAN 2019

I am working here on full-stack environment but Python Django and Angular are the mostly used Technologies in my job.

NHIIT, Multan — Python Instructor

DEC 2016 - MAR 2017

During my short stay at Multan, I taught python to starters.

Akbar Computer Academy, Loralai — IT Instructor

NOV 2015 - MAR 2016

I was an instructor of hardware and some other computer basics.

EDUCATION

Udacity, Intro to Deep learning with Pytorch

NOV 2018 - Present

Boys Degree College, Loralai — *Fsc(Faculty of Science)*

MAR 2013 - AUG 2015

Farooqi Public High School, Ziarat — *Matriculation*

MAR 2011 - AUG 2012

PROJECTS

Inventory Web App — asadliam.pythonanywhere.com

Inventory web app for wholesalers.

Checkout my Github for my work.

SUMMARY

I am a self-taught, highly passionate Developer and hobbyist. I've used a vast amount of online resources to learn various aspects of computer science in which I have deep interest. My primary source of computer science knowledge has been the MIT Opencourseware and some other too.

I spend time on <u>Projecteuler.net</u>, <u>Hackerrank.com</u> and <u>Google foo.bar</u> to sharp my problem solving and coding skills which turns out to be a lot of fun. I also do mock interviews on <u>Pramp</u>.

My primary expertise is in Algorithms, advanced Python programming and writing Django based web applications and also Ipython/Jupyter-notebook. I've used JS for only solving puzzles.

SKILLS

Python, Django, REST-API, Flask, Git, JS/ES6, AngularJS, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, Basic C/C++, DS, Algorithm design and analysis, Bootstrap 4, Data Analysis with Pandas

Links

Portfolio

GitHub

LinkedIn

Twitter

Skype: asadullah.itcgsc

LANGUAGES

English, Urdu, Pashto, Persian (Farsi) basic